hello
folks what I have here is a a present in
a sense from manual life Vitality it is
let how it look if it is what it
is what do we
have uh Alpha watch that's right my
manual life Vitality 2-year contract
with the old watch has finished and I
managed to pay off the entire watch
that's the one I'm wearing right here I
paid nothing for this thing and
basically as long as I
exercised um over 24 months of the
contract quote
unquote I achieved enough points to not
have to pay anything for this watch per
month so essentially I got it for free
well truth is you have to pay taxes on
the original purchase amount so I think
it would have been retailing for like
$269 a few years ago taxes on that would
have been about $30
$40 and that's all you pay and then all
the balance of it was free because I
earned enough points per month to pay it
off so 2 years later we have now another
opportunity to get a watch if I can just
open this thing up um oh here we
go let's see what we got here so let's
unbox this now this time because I was
able to pay off the old watch I Didn't I
could have gotten another free uh Apple
watch this is I think Gen 2 or three
anyway now they give out the SE for free
but why stop there why not get the
better watch which is the
series
nine
okay and there's the band this is the
watch um how do I open this see series
N and I mean yes you could pay more each
uh upgrade costs a bit more this one
because you have to pay tax on the
retail amount and it is an upgrade from
the SE they charge you
$97 plus the tax on the actual watch so
the actual watch would have been about
500 something plus the so the taxes on
that would have been about $60 or so so
after you add it all up it's about $140
$150 for the
watch um still not a bad deal especially
if you manage to exercise enough and
I've proven that I was able to over the
last two years same number of points
needed per month also even though you
get more um more of a discount uh s to
speak every time you get your point
allowance for the month
um this is an always on watch which is a
difference between that in the SE which
was the the version that would would be
uh provided otherwise and you could have
gone for the W watch Ultra but I didn't
want to get the watch Ultra because the
cost for that would have been way way
higher it would have they asked for a
lot of money but there's the watch
there that's the back of it series 9 41
aluminum ceramic
case okay and I'm going to go set this
up once I install the band this is a
sport band let's open this up as
well and now I know this watch is not
exactly new it's been out on the market
for a while uh but they did revamp
manual life Vitality over the last uh
few months cuz I was waiting and waiting
and waiting to get my new watch uh even
in October I finished paying it off by
then and here we are it's waited a few
wants to actually get permission to to
order another one because they were I
guess trying to come up with some deal
uh that they were um figuring out with
either apple or whatever their supplier
okay so as far as sizing goes now keep
in mind I have a uh a protector on this
one so it does look about the same size
but that's not true once this has a
protector on it'll look a little bigger
and it is larger I think this one was 38
mm and uh this one is
41 but like I said the always on feature
is great um this band I guess this part
goes on the top right cuz it goes like
this so that goes on top here just
slides
in you remember how this
works
hopefully oh at an angle there we go and
it's in and then this
one will slide in also at an
angle that's
it okay there you have it so look
forward to trying this out turning it on
charging it uh it does come with the
requisite cable that's about it no um no
wall dongle
you're just basically getting a uh you
know the the charging base and you have
to plug it into to now a
USB C okay that's I believe difference
as well I have my old one came with just
USB uh whatever a I guess the regular
type the big one now you're on this
reversible one the reversible
USBC that's another difference and uh
the other thing I noticed is
that this thing has a little bit of a
metallic sort of shape or color texture
to it top is still white plastic it
looks like but the base and the
surrounding area here is like a a shiny
metallic aluminum and the cord is
braided you see it's a braided
cord
so that's the watch uh it sticks see
magnetic still
and there you have
it hey guys well it turns out that the
Apple um Watch series 9 requires iOS 17
or later to allow it to pair to phone
this one here was on 16 something so I
have to update it I believe it's an
iPhone 11 or 12 my old phone here is an
iPhone 8 and the one I'm filming with
now this uh the one that that's pointing
right here that I was about to use is an
iPhone x but it's up to dat and it's
only version 16 something I'm not I
think you have to have an
XS in order to allow it to be Advanced
to iPhone IOS 17 so if you're getting a
watch one thing to watch out for is that
they do have requirements I just read up
that also the SE and the ultra will
require the latest IOS 17 and greater
and so if you have an X or an iPhone
8 um I believe you cannot update it at
this point to iOS 17 cuz I'm only on 16
something on both of my X and
8 and that's it it's not giving me an
option to update to 17 XS must be a
different uh phone I haven't looked it
up but I'm assuming it's a larger or
more recent version of the x that came
later I'm not exactly sure um but yeah
it looks like apple wants you to upgrade
and have your entire ecosystem at the
latest and uh greatest level maybe to
ensure proper performance so for now
this is my uh wife's phone I guess this
is going to be her watch I'll keep
exercising on this one to earn my points
which I believe doesn't matter whether
you use this watch or the old one as
long as you're working out it's tallying
the points anyway so in a sense I'll
still pay off this watch um with my
workouts although I'll be recording it
on this
watch all right so that's a quick
update so hope you enjoyed this uh quick
unboxing video uh thanks for watching
and uh catch you next time bye for now